TOM ZAZUETA

tomzazueta@gmail.com • (408) 391-4306 linkedin.com/in/zazueta • San Jose, CA

MY BACKGROUND

Having worked in the technology and marketing industry for most of my career, I have over 10 years of account and relationship management experience.

I am a humble and articulate systems thinker that loves building strong relationships and solving tough challenges.

INTERESTS

Fascinated by computer vision and, as a lifelong learner, I am currently enrolled in a machine learning course using Python and TensorFlow to build neural networks with Keras.

TOOLS

Very comfortable building tools and have the extensive knowledge in Microsoft's suite of tools, including spreadsheets and databases. I also have experience implementing Salesforce and HubSpot CRMs.

EDUCATION

San Jose State University

B.S., Computers in Art & Design, Research, and Education (C.A.D.R.E.)

(Multi-disciplinary degree examining visual computing and human-computer interfaces)

Graduated with Honors

MIT Sloan School of Management

Digital Business Strategy
Certificate, March 2021
(Intensive six-week executive
education course focused on digital
transformation and the future of
work)

WORK EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS CONSULTANT, OCT 2020-Present

Consultant at Sound Union, Inc.: Early-stage startup, Rehearsal and Social Club for Prosumer Musicians, Redwood City, CA.

- Built the financial model, operating budget, and staffing plan for the next 5-years
- Developed business strategy and plan for all subscription and unlimited membership plans
- Business strategist and thought partner with CEO and founder of Sound Union
- Defined product and service experience for members, including mobile app and referral program

CHIEF MARKETING OFFICER, JUL 2016 - OCT 2020

Buckingham Wealth Partners, LLC: Financial Services Industry - B2C and B2B wealth management firm that brings advisors and clients together. San Jose, CA / St. Louis, MO

- Drove brand strategy, positioning and messaging with partner agency including primary consumer research and creative direction
- Built a customer engagement scoring system using Salesforce to measure and predict engagement levels of key customers
- Developed comprehensive marketing plan and budgets based on competitive intelligence, annual ROI, and outcome targets
- Collaborated with sales and IT, delivering technology integrations with new marketing tools for better data capture and reporting
- Employed behavioral analytics to target ideal clients using CRM, AI, and automation software to deliver relevant messaging and content
- Designed a proposal generation tool to help with customer growth strategy and new client discovery
- Worked closely with sales and executive teams, helped grow organic and inorganic assets from \$14B to \$17B in 2017

CHIEF MARKETING OFFICER, FEB 2015 - JUL 2016

iD Tech, Inc.: Private equity backed, largest national provider of technology education summer camps for K-12 students, Campbell, CA

- Orchestrated sales and marketing initiatives, for advertising, promotions, search engine optimization, brand, web, social media, market research, external partners, and customer service teams
- Hands-on direction and oversight of sales/customer service call center managing all calls, email, chat, and knowledge base
- Grew and measured key business metrics including customer acquisition costs, conversion rates, engagement, customer satisfaction, Net Promoter Scores (NPS), demand generation, return rates, and loyalty program

BOARDS/VOLUNTEERING

Silicon Valley Education Foundation (2007-2014)

Board member for nonprofit creating STEM education resources and programs for students and teachers in Silicon Valley

Valley Medical Center Foundation (2022- present)

Volunteer consultant to the executive director helping with business strategy, a comprehensive marketing plan, and an audit of existing systems and processes.

CEO, CHIEF MARKETING TECHNOLOGIST, JAN 2006 - JAN 2015

HyperRelevance, Inc.: Omnichannel, data-driven, strategic marketing agency (formerly Coakley Heagerty), San Jose, CA

- Account leadership experience. Managed all teams, including strategy, new business, client engagement, financial, creative, technology, integrated marketing programs, and operations
- Lead account manager for these clients: Charles Schwab, Cisco, Dell, Palo Alto Medical Foundation, Santana Row, and VMware
- Grew and mentored a team of 35+ agency professionals and helped attract, develop, and retain strong internal and external talent
- Defined customer journeys, user experiences, and delivered solutions to provide better customer experiences for our clients

SENIOR PROGRAM MANAGER, MAR 2003 - JAN 2006

eBay, Inc.: Leading online global auction site, San Jose, CA

- Ensured business requirements, product positioning, attention to detail, project delivery, product presentations, and international coordination of all product launches; initial global release was in 32 cities, 16 countries, and in 10 languages
- Managed the Global Product Planning software engineering and quality assurance (QA) teams responsible for designing, building, and maintaining a flexible, end-to-end, product development lifecycle management platform. This workflow tool tracked every project scheduled for release to ebay.com (concept, scoping, resource allocation, QA, release, and analytics)
- Delivered key fraud prevention engineering projects on ebay.com in collaboration with the Trust & Safety division of eBay

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER, JAN 1999 - MAR 2003

Foveon, Inc.: Led product management for a VC funded, fabless-semiconductor startup developing disruptive CMOS digital image sensors, digital photography software, and professional digital cameras

- Developed and managed product pricing, user input, competitive analysis, product requirements, roadmaps, field operations, and delivery schedules
- User experience requirements, field testing, field support, and live demos of software and hardware
- Managed go-to-market strategy, customer research, and large partnerships in the US, Japan, and Europe

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Project Management, CKS Group, Inc.: Worked crossfunctionally in integrated marketing communications agency

Marketing Intern, Apple, Inc.: Managed the "Made on Apple" program for Architecture, Engineering, and Construction vertical